Cleiton Elias de Barros Moura

Rio de Janeiro (24) 99208-0658 Cleiton.barrosmoura@gmail.com

Site | LinkedIn

Summary

Frontend developer specializing in creating responsive pages with reusable components, animations, visual effects, and attractive minimalist designs. My main technologies are ReactJS, TypeScript, and Tailwind, but I also have experience with a range of other tools and technologies, including HTML, CSS, SASS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, PHP, Next.js, Figma, and WordPress. Currently, I am responsible for the development, maintenance, and analysis of multiple projects, focusing on performance improvements and enhancing existing projects.

Education:

 Information Systems - Faculdade de Ciências Econômicas, Administrativas e da Computação Dom Bosco (2020)

Experience:

Ignis Digital | Frontend Developer | 04/2024 - Current

- Development and maintenance systems using Next.js, ReactJS, and React Native Expo.
- I work closely with the business and backend teams, analyzing and providing maintenance to multiple projects.
- Mapping and refactoring legacy code to improve system performance.
- Implement animations, and visual effects to enhance user engagement with lib as frame motion and AOS.
- State management using Tanstack, form management controlling component data with React Hook Form, and analysis and validation of field values with Yup.

Rizer | Frontend Developer | 10/2023 - 01/2024

- Front-end development, focusing on using Next.js and TypeScript to create dynamic pages in a structured manner.
- Creation of responsive layouts with Tailwind CSS, providing agile and consistent styling. Utilized resources such as tailwind-merge, clsx, and NextUI to develop reusable components, facilitating intuitive maintenance.
- Optimized frontend to achieve excellent performance scores on Google PageSpeed.
- Integrated next-auth to manage login and authorization, simplifying authenticated workflows. Adopted form validation with react-hook-form and zod for a more intuitive and secure approach, ensuring data consistency and REST API consumption.

Lacrei Saúde | Frontend Developer | 01/2023 – 06/2023

- I contributed solutions aligned with the project's needs, playing a role as a front-end developer in the development and maintenance of interfaces.
- Development and optimization of reusable and adaptable components, emphasizing code scalability and the implementation of a responsive front-end, ensuring seamless adaptation across various devices and screen sizes.
- Performed code reviews to maintain quality and ensure adherence to best coding practices.
- I worked closely with the UX/UI team to deliver the best possible user experience.

Empório High-Tech | Frontend Web Developer | 06/2022 – 10/2022

- Develop institutional websites and web pages using WordPress, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, PHP, and jQuery.
- Responsible for defining the website's objectives, navigation structure, and requirements.
- Ensure the site functions correctly, troubleshoot issues, and guarantee quality; perform updates, fixes, and ensure the site continues to function effectively.
- I worked in collaboration with the development and design teams to ensure a product where the layouts are visually appealing and function well within the context of the site.

Languages:

Portuguese - Native English - Intermediate Spanish - Intermediate French - Beginner